<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SIGTURK</title><link>https://sigturk.com/</link><description>Recent content on SIGTURK</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sigturk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://sigturk.com/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calendar</title><link>https://sigturk.com/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/calendar/</guid><description>For announcement and news, please join our mailing list or take a look at the archive at archive.</description></item><item><title>Code of Ethics and Conduct</title><link>https://sigturk.com/coec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/coec/</guid><description>Introduction SIGTURK is the ACL Special Interest Group on Turkic Languages that aims to foster community brainstorming and collaboration on events and resources for the public good in open source etiquette. As these processes involve sync and async communication, this document specifies professional standards all participants of SIGTURK and SIGTURK-related dialogue agree to uphold to promote formal reliability of SIGTURK outputs, respect, competence, responsibility, and integrity while recognizing the rapidly changing society and the necessity to exercise more considerable caution in this spirit by every participant.</description></item><item><title>Constitution</title><link>https://sigturk.com/constitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/constitution/</guid><description>PDF version
I. TURKIC LANGUAGES Turkic language family includes approximately half a billion speakers around the world
Specially focused around the geographical range across the Eurasian continent
The status of recognition and formalization of the languages may range from national status to critically endangered
From the scientific perspective, the Turkic languages form a unique working ground, marked by a striking structural similarity, as well as an easily recognizable shared core vocabulary and inflectional inventory, which span the entire group of languages.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://sigturk.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/contact/</guid><description>For more information, please email contact [at] sigturk [dot] com.</description></item><item><title>Docs</title><link>https://sigturk.com/docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/docs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>News</title><link>https://sigturk.com/news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/news/</guid><description>For announcement and news, please join our mailing list or take a look at the archive at archive.
SIGTURK News Archive</description></item><item><title>People</title><link>https://sigturk.com/people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/people/</guid><description>Executive Committee President Duygu Ataman (email) (GitHub)
Secretary Sardana Ivanova (email) (GitHub)
Officers Mehmet Oguz Derin (GitHub)
Mammad Hajili (GitHub)
Abdullatif Köksal (GitHub)
Aziza Mirsaidova (GitHub)
Jonne Sälevä (GitHub)
Organization Contributors Deniz Zeyrek Bozşahin, Middle East Technical University (Webpage)
Necva Bölücü, CSIRO (Webpage)</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://sigturk.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/projects/</guid><description>Previous Projects The Turkic Interlingua (TIL) Multilingual Corpus for Machine Translation was a project conducted by our community that resulted in state-of-the-art pre-trained machine translation systems as well as multi-way parallel training and evaluation resources in 22 Turkic languages. For more details, please visit the project GitHub page: https://github.com/turkic-interlingua/til-mt
Ongoing Projects We are currently establishing standards and methodology for building a large-scale multilingual Turkic Corpus that would have linguistic annotations to be used for developing and evaluating systems for solving natural language processing tasks, such as past-of-speech tagging, named entity recognition, text summarization, and question answering.</description></item><item><title>Register</title><link>https://sigturk.com/register/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/register/</guid><description>To start joining membership, you should fill out the form.
Registration Form You can become a member of SIGTURK and be updated on recent information and activities by joining our communication channels on Telegram and Slack.</description></item><item><title>Workshop</title><link>https://sigturk.com/workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sigturk.com/workshop/</guid><description>Introduction We are excited to announce the First Annual Meeting of the ACL Special Interest Group on Turkic Languages, held in conjunction with Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics in Bangkok, Thailand. Our primary aim is to provide a new venue to foster research on computational linguistics in Turkic languages. By co-locating with ACL, we seek to facilitate interaction among researchers from diverse backgrounds, encouraging the exchange of ideas and the presentation of cutting-edge work in natural language processing (NLP) specific to Turkic languages.</description></item></channel></rss>